The true story of a legend.
Great Balls of Fire! is a drama, history, music film directed by Jim McBride.
The story of Jerry Lee Lewis, arguably the greatest and
certainly one of the wildest musicians of the 1950s.
His arrogance, remarkable talent, and unconventional lifestyle often brought him into conflict with
others in the industry, and even earned him the scorn and condemnation of the public.
Jerry Lee Lewis, played by Dennis Quaid.
Myra Gale Brown, played by Winona Ryder.
J.W. Brown, played by John Doe.
Jud Phillips, played by Stephen Tobolowsky.
Jimmy Swaggart, played by Alec Baldwin.
Lois Brown, played by Lisa Blount.
Great Balls of Fire!
is a 1989 American biographical drama film directed by Jim McBride and
starring Dennis Quaid as rockabilly pioneer Jerry Lee Lewis.
Based on a biography by Myra Lewis and Murray M.
Silver Jr., the screenplay is written by McBride and Jack Baran.
The film is produced by Adam Fields, with executive producers
credited as Michael Grais, Mark Victor, and Art Levinson.
The film depicts the early career of Lewis, from his rise to rock-and-roll stardom to his
controversial marriage to his 13-year-old cousin that led to his downfall.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll, musician, train, older man
younger woman relationship, religious fundamentalism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.